BRIAN CHARLES O'REILLY

FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

416.998.2473 | BRIANCHARLESOREILLY@GMAIL.COM briancharlesoreilly.com | github.com/briancharlesoreilly

PERSONAL BACKGROUND

A creative at heart with solid leadership and managerial experience in the hospitality industry as a small business owner. Classical training in solid wood cabinet making led to several years of bespoke furniture design and building, rounding out a lively and unique work history. Quick to learn, highly adaptable, with a penchant for forward thinking and novel technologies. Outside of work you'll find me reading a book (bury me in the library) and dabbling in video game design.

SKILLS

- HTML5
- CSS3 and SCSS
- Responsive Web Design
- Web Accessibility Standards
- Javascript (es6) & jQuery
- React
- RESTful APIs & Firebase
- Python (learning)
- Solidity (learning)
- AWS Certification (learning)

SPECIALIZATIONS

- Team Building
- Planning & Logistics
- Advanced Financial Literacy
- Budget Forecasting
- Revenue Growth
- Innovative Technological Adaptation
- Small Business Acumen

PROJECTS

- Dungeons & Dragons class companion app (jQuery API, html5 and css3)
- Event planner/social media site (axios API, firebase, react)

WHERE:

Cell: (416) 998 2473 Email: briancharlesoreilly@gmail.com Location: West End, Toronto ON

WORK HISTORY

Bar Manager / Owner NORTHERN BELLE, 2015 - 2021

- Created short, mid, and long term roadmap in competitive industry.
- Provided successful cost-reduction solutions during pandemic (temporary 40% reduction in fixed monthly overhead & rent relief).
- Grew business from debt governed inception (- \$80k debt in 2017) to cash positive state suitable for expansion or sale (+ 200k evaluation in 2021)
- Researched and updated technological assets to streamline operations while respecting traditional sector needs.

Cabinet Maker & Furniture Design SON OF A WOODCUTTER, 2016 - 2018

- Designed, milled, and manufactured bespoke solid wood furniture for high end clients.
- Digital marketing of company catalog through social media.
- Pivoted between front facing customer service role and back end design, creation and distribution of product.

Bar & Cafe Manager NORTHWOOD, 2013 - 2015

- NORTHWOOD, 2015 2015
- Inventory / Product supply chain director.Oversaw employee hiring, training & product knowledge.
- Scheduled staff of 15 20.
- Directly controlled budgetary spending, and setting / expanding revenue goals for business doing \$315, 000 sales a year (pre pandemic).

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

Juno College of Technology (Toronto ON)WEB DEVELOPMENT IMMERSIVE BOOTCAMP, 2022

- Web development HTML & CSS accelerated program
- JavaScript accelerated program

Humber College (Toronto ON)CABINET MAKING, 2016

- Deans list with Honours

St. Francis Xavier University (Antigonish NS) BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION. 2004

- Partial Degree - Deans list with Honours

J.L. Ilsley High School (Halifax NS) HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA, 2003

- Vice President of Student Council
- Winner of Regional High School Robotics competition.
- Party Leader of Model Parliament.
- Mathlete